A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1961-1962
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1961-1962
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.651
This collection consists of 19,800 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 20 May 1965.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- General Files, 1961-1962
  - "A - Am" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Academic Deans 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - January - June 1961 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - July - December 1961 - June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Panel on ROTC Affairs 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Air Force and Air Force ROTC 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Chapters Planned 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Birmingham Chapter 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Charleston, West Virginia 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Charles Town, West Virginia 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Charlotte, North Carolina 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Danville 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Lynchburg 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Memphis 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Peninsula Chapter 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Philadelphia 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Richmond 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Tidewater Tri-Country 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Washington Chapter (University of Virginia Club of Washington) 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Wilmington, Delaware 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Winchester 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Fund 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Speeches (see Speeches) (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities (See Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges) 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - American Association of University Professors 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "X - Y - Z" 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Architecture 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Army - General 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's School 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Army - ROTC 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Art 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Art Commission 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Universities 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Colleges 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Astronomy 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: January - June 1961 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: July - December 1961 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Athletic Director and Football Coach 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Athletics - Invitations to Board of Visitors 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC) 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - Atlantic Coast Conference Minutes, Vol. I 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - Atlantic Coast Conference Minutes, Vol. II 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - Football: University of South Carolina Game, Commonwealth Day - 4 November 1961 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - Football: William and Mary Game, 23 September 1961 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - Football: North Carolina State, Homecoming- 7 October 1961 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - Football: University of Maryland, High School Senior Day- 25 November 1961 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - N.C.A.A. 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - "Ba - Bl" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - "Bm - Bz" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Biology 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Blandy Farm 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Mountain Lake (Biology File) 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Bolivian Seminar, April 1961 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Budget Requests 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Budget Exhibits - All Divisions 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Planning Department 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - General 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Clinch Valley College (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Copeley Hill 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Field House (see University Hall) (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - George Mason College (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - Life Science Building (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Building Program - University Hall (see also Field House) (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Bureau of Pubic Administration 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Bursar 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - "Cl - Ca" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Calendar for Deans 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Foundation 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Cavalier Daily 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Chancellor 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Chemistry 1961-1962 (Box 7)
  - Chemistry Building 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Civil Defense 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Classics 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Clinch Valley College 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Clippings 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Commerce, McIntire Undergraduate School of 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Commission on Public Education 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Comission on State Capital Outlay and Means of Financing 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - Commissions, Studies, etc. (see Legislative Program) (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - College of Arts and Sciences, January - April 1961-1962 (Box 8)
  - College of Arts and Sciences - May - June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - College of Arts and Sciences - July - December 1962 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - College of Arts and Sciences - January - June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Council on Education, American 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Academic Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Administrative 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Admissions (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Arboretum Advisory 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Architectural Advisory 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Athletic 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Calendar 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Calendar of Events (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Catalogue 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Cemetery 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Chapel (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Chemistry Building 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley Advisory 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley Science Building (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Community Colleges 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Community Colleges Building 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Combustion Center (see National Damage) 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Contractual Relations 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Dormitory Counselors 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Dormitories 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Field House 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Foreign Nationals 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Fraternities 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Fulbright Awards (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Housing 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Institutional Analysis 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Lectures, Special 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Long Range Planning 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Married Student Housing 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Objects of Art 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Orientation 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Public Occasions 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Processions 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Public Relations 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Registration 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Scholarships, Loans and Employment 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Student Activities 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Students, University 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Teacher Education 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Traffic 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Tree 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Undergraduates 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Committee - University Press 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Records 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Union 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Virginia Status of University Students (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Wilson Gee Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Community Colleges Proposed - (see Extension Centers) (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Community Colleges Proposed - Clifton Forge, Covington (see Extension Centers) (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Community Colleges Proposed - Lynchburg (see Extension Centers) (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Computer Center 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Comptroller 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Confidential Reports (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Cooper, Weldon 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Copeley Hill 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Council on American Graduate Education 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 12)
  - Darden, C. W., Jr. 1961-1962 (Box 12)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 12)
  - Economics 1961-1962 (Box 12)
  - Education 1961-1962 (Box 12)
  - Educational Research, Bureau of 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Educational T. V. 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Endowment Fund - Alumni Board of Trustees (Centennial) 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Engineering - January - June 1961 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Engineering - July - June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - English 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Enrollment 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Extension Centers Proposed 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Extension Division 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Extension Center (Proposed) - Clifton Forge, Covington 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Extension Center (Proposed) - Lynchburg 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Extension Center (Proposed) - Madison 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Extension Center (Proposed) - Martinsville 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Extension Center (Proposed) - Northern Virginia Branch 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - Extension Center (Proposed) - Roanoke 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Faculty 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Faculty Minutes 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Faulkner Foundation 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Cross 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Finals - 1961 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Finals - 1962 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Food Service (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 15)
  - Ford Foundation (see also Jefferson Center and Economics) 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Foreign Affairs 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Founder's Day 1961 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Founder's Day 1962 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Fraternity - Chi Psi 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Fraternities 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Fund for Adult Education 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - General Assembly - (see also Legislative Program) 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Geography 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Geology 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - George Mason College - (see also Building Program - George Mason College) 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Gifts and Grants - January - June 1961-1962 (Box 17)
  - Gifts and Grants - July - December 1961 - June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 17)
  - Governor's Office - 1961 - 12 January 1962 1961-1962 (Box 17)
  - Governor's Office - 13 January 1962 - 30 June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 17)
  - Governor's Office - Advices of Allotment - 1961 - 30 June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 17)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1961-1962 (Box 18)
  - "Ha - Hk" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 18)
  - "Ho - Hk" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 18)
  - Harrison, Albertis S., Jr. (see Governor's Office as of 13 January 1962) 1961-1962 (Box 18)
  - Highway Department 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - History 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Honor Committee 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Honors Courses 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Hospital - Dedication 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Housing (see also Housing Committee) 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Information Services (see also Public Relations and Development) 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Institute of International Education 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "A" 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "B" 1961-1962 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - "C" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "D" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "E" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "F" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "G" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "H" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "I" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "J" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "K" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "L" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "M" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "N" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "O" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "P" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "Q" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "R" 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "S" 1961-1962 (Box 21)
  - Invitations - "T" 1961-1962 (Box 21)
  - Invitations - "U" 1961-1962 (Box 21)
  - Invitations - "V" 1961-1962 (Box 21)
  - Invitations - "W" 1961-1962 (Box 21)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1961-1962 (Box 21)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 22)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 22)
  - Law School 1961-1962 (Box 22)
  - Lectures - General 1961-1962 (Box 22)
  - Legal Matters 1961-1962 (Box 22)
  - Legislative Program 1961-1962 (Box 22)
  - Library 1961-1962 (Box 22)
  - Library - Board of Alderman 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - Life Science Building 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - Loan Funds (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - McConnell Award (see Thomas Jefferson Award) (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - McConnell Foundation (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - "M - Me" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - Mace 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - Madison, James, The Papers of 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - Mary Washington College - January - June 1961 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - Mary Washington College - July - December 1961 1961-1962 (Box 23)
  - Mary Washington - January - June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 24)
  - Mathematics 1961-1962 (Box 24)
  - Maxwell Air Force Base 1961-1962 (Box 24)
  - Medicine - January - June 1961 1961-1962 (Box 24)
  - Medicine - July - December 1961 1961-1962 (Box 24)
  - Medicine - January - June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 24)
  - Modern Language 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - Music 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - National Association of sate Universities 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - National Damage Assessment Center (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - National Science Foundation 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - Navy - General 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - Navy - R.O.T.C. 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - Newcomb Hall 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - Newcomen Society 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - Newman Hall 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - News Letter 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - Nursing 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - Old Dominion Foundation 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - "P - Ph" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - "Pi - Pz" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - Personnel 1961-1962 (Box 26)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Philosophy 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Photographs 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Physics 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Political Science 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Possible Donors 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Presidents' Council 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Psychiatric Institute 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Psychology 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Public Occasions (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Public Relations (see also Information Services) 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Purchasing 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Questionnaires 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Radiation Protection 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Radio 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Raven Society 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Recommendations 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Religion 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Remington Rand (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Requisitions 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Research (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Richardson Foundation 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Romance Languages 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - Rural Social Economics 1961-1962 (Box 28)
  - "Sa - Sl" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 29)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 29)
  - Salaries 1961-1962 (Box 29)
  - Senate 1961-1962 (Box 29)
  - Seven Society 1961-1962 (Box 29)
  - Southern Association of Colleges 1961-1962 (Box 29)
  - Squid Project 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - State Board of Education 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - State Council of Higher Education 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - State Department of Education 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - State Department of Health 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - State Universities Association 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - Statistics 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - Student Affairs 1961-1962 (Box 30)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Sociology 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Southern Fellowship Fund (see also Council of Southern Universities) 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Southern Humanities Conference 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Southern Regional Education Board 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Southern Universities (see also Council of Southern Universities) 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Southern University Conference 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Space Study (folder empty) 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Speech and Drama 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Speeches and Articles 1961-1962 (Box 31)
  - Student Affairs 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - Student Aid Office 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - Student Council 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - Student Health Department 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - Summer Session 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - Talbott, Frank, Jr. 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - Traffic Control 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - Travel 1961-1962 (Box 32)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - U. S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - U. S. Department of State 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - United States Steel Foundation, Inc. 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - University Center in Virginia 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - University Hall 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - University Houses 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - University News Service (see Information Services) 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - University Press 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - University Theater (sit-ins) 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Junior Academy of Science 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Education Association 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes - April 1962 1961-1962 (Box 33)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes - February 1961 1961-1962 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes - June 1961 1961-1962 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Board Committees 1961-1962 (Box 34)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes - June 1962 1961-1962 (Box 35)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes - February 1962 1961-1962 (Box 35)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes - December 1961 1961-1962 (Box 35)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes - October 1961 1961-1962 (Box 35)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes - April 1961 1961-1962 (Box 35)
  - Visitors - Coxe, Mr. Whitwell W. 1961-1962 (Box 35)
  - Visitors - Jones, Mrs. B. T., Jr. 1961-1962 (Box 35)
  - Visitors - McWane, Mr. Henry E. 1961-1962 (Box 35)
  - Visitors - Board Executive Committee 1961-1962 (Box 36)
  - "Wa - Wh" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 36)
  - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 36)
  - Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies 1961-1962 (Box 36)
  - Women, Dean of 1961-1962 (Box 36)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 36)
  - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) 1961-1962 (Box 36)